Register of the Richard Paul Mitchell collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Geographic File, 1906-1983, undated (Boxes 13-21)
  - Europe, 1972-1981
    Contains files from "Europe and the Middle East" listed in the alphabetical topic file in Mitchell's clipping file index.
    - General, 1973-1974, 1980 (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - Oil, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 16: 2)
      Includes the article "Japan's Oil Line to Mideast."
    - Relations with the Middle East, 1972-1981 (Box-folder 16: 3)
  - Japan, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 16: 4)
  - Levant, 1957-1983, undated
    See also: "Turkey - Greece - Cyprus"
    - Iraq, 1957-1980 (Box-folder 16: 5)
    - Iraq-Iran War, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 16: 6-7)
    - Israel, 1972-1981, undated
      See also: Black Africa - Israel
      - General, 1974-1981 (Box-folder 16: 8, Box-folder 17: 1)
      - Internal affairs, 1973-1978, undated (Box-folder 17: 2-4)
        Includes the paper "Aspects of Recent Israeli Military Expansion" by Don Bumpus, written for a class taught by Mitchell.
      - Occupied territories, 1972-1981 (Box-folder 17: 5)
    - Jerusalem, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 17: 6)
    - Jordan, 1957, 1973-1983 (Box-folder 17: 7)
    - Lebanon, 1959-1981 (Box-folder 18: 1-2)
      Includes the report Lebanon: Crisis and Challenge in the Arab World from the Association of Arab-American University Graduates
    - Lebanon vs. Palestinians, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 18: 3)
    - Syria, 1973-1982 (Box-folder 18: 4-5)
  - "Non-Arab Southwest Asia,", 1963-1983, undated
    - Afghanistan, 1973-1983
      - General, 1973-1983 (Box-folder 18: 6-7)
      - U.S. policy, 1973, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 19: 1)
      - U.S. response to Soviet Invasion, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 19: 2)
    - Iran, 1963-1982, undated
      - Historical file, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 19: 3)
        Contains articles related to Iran prior to the 1979 revolution.
      - Internal affairs, 1963, undated (Box-folder 19: 4)
        Contains the typescript "Political Organization in Iran Since 1945: From Dowreh to Political Party" by an unidentified author and "Middle East Paradox--The 'Beggar Rich'" from The New York Times Magazine.
      - Minorities in Iran, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 19: 5)
      - Miscellaneous, 1980-1982, undated (Box-folder 19: 6)
    - Pakistan, 1973-1983 (Box-folder 19: 7-8)
  - North Africa, 1906-1983
    - General, 1973-1983 (Box-folder 19: 9)
    - Algeria, 1906-1980 (Box-folder 19: 10)
      The majority of the articles are from 1973 and 1980, with three clippings from the 1960s and a photocopy of an article from 1906.
    - Libya, 1963, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 20: 1-2)
    - Libyan plane incident, 1973 (Box-folder 20: 3)
      Contains articles relating to a Libyan airliner that was shot down over the Sinai Peninsula by two Israeli jet fighters on February 21, 1973.
    - Morocco, 1965, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 20: 4)
      Contains several articles from French publications.
    - Tunisia, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 20: 5)
  - "Turkey - Greece - Cyprus,", 1972-1983
    - Armenians, 1980 May 25 (Box-folder 20: 6)
    - Greece, 1972-1974, 1980 (Box-folder 20: 7)
    - Turkey, 1972-1983 (Box-folder 20: 8-9)
    - Turkish coup d'etat, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 20: 10)
    - Unfiled articles, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 20: 11)
      Contains clippings related to Turkey, Greece, and Cyprus.
  - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (USSR), 1973-1981
    Includes the files from the USSR file listed under the alphabetical topic file in Mitchell's clipping file index.
    - Foreign policy, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 21: 1)
    - Internal affairs, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 21: 2)
    - Relations with the Middle East, 1973-1981 (Box-folder 21: 3)
    - US relations, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 21: 4)
- Subject File, 1933-1983, undated (Boxes 21-36)
  Clippings, photocopies of articles, notes, pamphlets, booklets, and other printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject. Material mainly in English, with some items in Arabic and French.
  Groupings and file titles are based on Mitchell's index, located in the Richard P. Mitchell File, and his original file names; however, some file names have been modified for clarity. Not all files listed on the index appear in the collection. Also, not all files in the collection are reflected in the index.
  - Arab-Israeli conflict, 1968-1982, undated
    - General, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 21: 5-6)
    - Expansionism, 1968-1972, undated (Box-folder 21: 7)
      Includes the booklets: Facts of Israeli Expansion Lebensraum, Israel in Reality, Israeli Expansionism, and Palestine: Illustrated Political History.
    - Israeli raids on Lebanon, 1972-1981 (Box-folder 21: 8)
    - Palestinian conflict, 1980 (Box-folder 21: 9)
    - Settlement, 1973-1974, 1978 (Box-folder 21: 10)
    - US perspectives and participation, 1972-1978 (Box-folder 22: 1-2)
      Includes a summary of a visit to the Middle East by A. T. Sullivan from July 4-August 9, 1974 describing his impressions of current Arab-Israeli relations, as well as a document titled, "The Present Stage of the Arab-Israeli Conflict" by Bernard Lewis.
    - "The Value of Human Life,", 1969-1973 (Box-folder 22: 3)
      Contains clippings discussing whether or not violence is ever justified.
    - Wars (1948 and 1967), 1973, undated (Box-folder 22: 4)
      Contains photocopies of articles related to Arab-Israeli wars in 1948 and 1967. Also included is the June 1973 edition of the magazine Middle East International.
    - Yom Kippur War, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 22: 5-6)
    - Zionist terror, 1972, 1977 (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - Unfiled articles, 1972-1982, undated (Box-folder 22: 8-9, Box-folder 23: 1-2)
      Contains various clippings and photocopies of articles on the Arab-Israeli conflict. Also incudes a booklet titled The Role of International Law in Achieving Justice and Peace in Palestine-Israel by W. T. Mallison, Jr. and S. V. Mallison.
  - Book reviews, 1978-1983, undated (Box-folder 23: 3)
    Contains notices and reviews of books related to topics represented in the Subject and Geographic Files. Includes a copy of the 1980 catalog for Schocken Books.
  - Camp David, 1973-1980
    - 1973-1977 (Box-folder 23: 4)
    - 1978 (Box-folder 23: 5-6)
    - 1979 (Box-folder 23: 7)
    - 1980 (Box-folder 24: 1-2)
    - Other countries, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 24: 3)
  - Detente, 1973-1980, undated (Box-folder 24: 4)
    Includes articles discussing the easing of hostilities between various countries and the U.S.
  - Energy, 1973-1977
    - General, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 24: 5-6, Box-folder 25: 1)
    - Ecology, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 25: 2)
    - "Energy: The Facts...the Fears...the Future," CBS News Special Report, transcript, 1977 August 31 (Box-folder 25: 3)
    - Policies, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 25: 4)
    - Oil, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 25: 5-6)
      See also: Oil subgrouping located later in this series.
  - Inter-Arab and inter-Islamic relations, 1933-1980, undated
    Contains materials listed as "Inter-Arab, Inter-Islamic" in Mitchell's inventory.
    - Arab League, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 25: 7)
    - Conferences, 1974 October (Box-folder 25: 8)
      Contains material on the 1974 Arab League summit in Rabat, Morocco.
    - Inter-Arab relations, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 25: 9)
    - Treaty of Friendship and Bon Voisinage between the Saudi Arabian Monarchy and the Emirate of Trans-Jordan, 1933 (Box-folder 25: 10)
      Contains two typescript copies of the treaty with handwritten edits. Also includes a paper with notes in English and Arabic.
    - Untitled research paper, circa 1974 (Box-folder 25: 11)
      Contains a copy of a research paper discussing inter-Arab relations in the context of the oil embargo and the Yom Kippur War, which was written for one of Mitchell's classes. The title page containing the author's name and title of the paper is missing.
    - Unfiled articles, 1978-1980, undated (Box-folder 25: 12)
  - Iran hostage crisis, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 26: 1-3)
    These files are listed in Mitchell's index as "The Hostage Crisis."
  - Iran hostage crisis: Foreign reaction, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 26: 4)
    Contains material from the file listed as "Foreign Reaction to the Hostage Crisis" in Mitchell's clipping file index.
  - Iranian Revolution, 1978-1980
    - General, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 26: 5, Box-folder 27: 1-2)
      Contains various articles related to the 1979 Iranian revolution. Includes an edition of Women and Revolution: Journal of the Women's Commission of the Spartacist League from Fall 1979.
    - Foreign reaction, 1978, 1980 (Box-folder 27: 3)
    - Internal affairs, 1978, 1980 (Box-folder 27: 4)
  - Islam, 1962-1982, undated
    - General, 1971-1980 (Box-folder 27: 5)
      Includes a copy of Afrique-Asie from November 1979, other articles in French, and booklets produced by the Islamic Foundation.
    - Islam and Muslim affairs, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 27: 6)
    - Islamic revival, 1976-1981, undated (Box-folder 27: 7)
      Includes copies of "Islamic Revivalism and the Search for Peace in the Middle East" by Eric M. Davis and "The Return of Islam" by Bernard Lewis. Also includes a typescript copy of the paper "Non-Muslims and the Islamic Revival" by William Hamblin, which was written for a history class taught by Mitchell and contains his written comments.
    - "Modern Muslim Movements and the Political Order" by I. A. Abu-Lughod, typescript, undated (Box-folder 27: 8)
    - Muslim Brotherhood, 1976-1982, undated (Box-folder 27: 9, Box-folder 28: 1-3)
      Contains a copy of the May 8-14, 1979 edition of the Executive Intelligence Review, as well as a copy of an Arabic magazine, pamphlets, photocopies of articles, and various clippings from Arabic and English publications. Also includes a copy of Gary S. Schiff's dissertation, "Religion and Political Legitimacy: Islam in Egypt 1952-1954," a copy of the script for a segment on Egypt from the BBC radio series Islam in the Modern World, and several handwritten English translations of articles originally written in Arabic.
    - "The Political Influence of Islam To-Day [sic],", 1962 May 11 (Box-folder 28: 4)
      Scope and contents note
      Photocopy of a an unidentified research department memorandum.
  - Jews, 1957-1983, undated
    - General, 1978-1980, undated (Box-folder 28: 5)
    - Anti-Semitism, 1957-1981 (Box-folder 28: 6)
      Contains the articles "Anti Semitism in the Gilded Age: A Reinterpretation" by John Higham (1957), "Arab Antisemites' [sic] Nazi Model" from Patterns of Prejudice (1972), and a news clipping about the increase in anti-Jewish acts in the neighborhood of Williamsburg in Brooklyn, New York (1981).
    - Jews outside Israel (non-Soviet), 1972-1974 (Box-folder 28: 7-8)
      Includes transcripts of excerpts from CBS Evening News with Walker Cronkite on September 17, October 1, and November 14, 1974.
    - Relations with Arabs and Christians in the US, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 28: 9)
    - Relations with Armenians, 1982-1983, undated (Box-folder 28: 10)
    - Soviet Jews, 1972-1974, undated (Box-folder 28: 11, Box-folder 29: 1)
      Contains the pamphlets Jews in the USSR and Socialists and the Fight Against Anti-Semitism, as well as a news clippings.
  - Modernization of the Middle East, 1972-1983 (Box-folder 29: 2)
    Mainly contains clippings from 1982 to 1983. Also includes a photocopy of the booklet Civilization and Modernization by Dr. Ali Shariati.
  - Oil, 1965-1981, undated
    See also: Energy
    - General, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 29: 3)
    - Continental Oil Company, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 29: 4)
      Contains pamphlets and copies of two speeches given by John G. McLean, Chairman and CEO of Continental Oil Company.
    - The Economist, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 29: 5)
      Contains "Middle East Oil on New Terms: A Survey by the Economist" as well as a clipping regarding oil from The New York Times and a copy of the Congressional Record from June 13, 1966 titled, "The Role of Private Enterprise in the Economic Development of the Middle East."
    - Energy alternatives and energy crisis, 1972-1981 (Box-folder 29: 6)
      Includes a copy of International Energy Problems, policy number 14, from the US State Department's Bureau of Public Affairs, dated July 17, 1979.
    - Finance (non-oil), 1973-1974, 1981 (Box-folder 29: 7)
      Contains articles related to trade, loans, and other finance decisions made between various countries in response to a rise in oil prices.
    - "Issues prior to 1978,", 1972-1974, 1980 (Box-folder 29: 8-9)
    - "The Oil Crisis: This Time the Wolf Is Here" by James E. Akins, Foreign Affairs, 1973 April (Box-folder 30: 1)
    - Oil producers (non-OPEC), 1979-1981 (Box-folder 30: 2)
    - "Oil and Security: Problems and Prospects of Importing Countries" by Edward N. Krapels, 1977 (Box-folder 30: 3)
    - Oil and the US, 1973-1977, undated (Box-folder 30: 4)
      Includes several pamphlets and the booklet U.S. Politics and Arab Oil: Some Nettles to Grasp by Elmer Berger.
    - Oil users, 1972, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 30: 5)
      Includes a copy of a speech given at the Mid-East Institute's 1972 Annual Meeting by James E. Akins titled, "Evolving Relationships among the Oil Companies, the Oil Producing Governments and the Major Consumers: Confrontation or Cooperation?"
    - Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC), 1978-1981 (Box-folder 30: 6)
    - Pipelines, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 30: 7)
      Includes articles regarding the Suez Canal.
    - "Talk Given by Liston F. Hills, Former Chairman and Chief Executive Officer of the Arabian American Oil Company (ARAMCO) to World Affairs Council, San Francisco, California, on February 15, 1974,", 1974 Februray 27 (Box-folder 30: 8)
  - Palestinians and the Palestine Liberation Organization (PLO), 1965-1983, undated
    - PLO, 1974-1983 (Box-folder 30: 9)
    - PLO at the United Nations, 1974, 1977 (Box-folder 30: 10)
    - Palestinians, 1965, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 31: 1)
      Includes the May 1973 edition of Revolution Africaine.
    - Refugees, 1973, 1977, undated (Box-folder 31: 2)
  - Pluralism, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 31: 3)
    Includes a letter from Mitchell regarding a proposal for a panel on pluralism during an American Historical Association meeting.
  - The Pope and the Catholic Church, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 31: 4)
  - Religious movements, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 31: 5)
  - Settlements in Israeli occupied territories, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 31: 6)
  - Shah Mohammad Reza Pahlavi, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 31: 7)
  - Superpowers and the Middle East, 1973-1981
    - France-Middle East policy, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 31: 8)
    - Indian Ocean, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 31: 9)
    - Reaction to 1979-1980 crisis (Box-folder 31: 10)
      Contains articles regarding the superpowers' reactions to the Soviet invasion of Afghanistan and the general uneasiness between European countries at the time.
    - US and its allies, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 31: 11)
    - Unfiled articles, 1973, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 31: 12)
      Contains articles regarding countries in the Middle East and relations with Great Britain, Japan, the United States, and the USSR.
  - Third World, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 31: 13)
    Includes a description of a course on Latin America as a Thrid World area and a typed summary of an article by Ernesto Laclau titled "Feudalism and Capitalism in Latin America."
  - Third World: Non-aligned nations, 1973 (Box-folder 32: 1)
  - US-Middle East policy, 1951-1980 (Box-folder 32: 2-5)
    Contains clippings and several pamphlets, including two copies of the pamphlet American Interests in the Middle East. Also includes a transcript of the lecture "Analysis of Strategic Areas: The Middle East" by Department of State official Edwin M. Wright and "The Tripartite Declaration of 25 May 1950: A Cornerstone of American Policy toward the Arab-Israeli Conflicts" produced by the Arab Information Center in New York.
  - US-Middle East policy: Senator Fulbright, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 32: 6)
  - Western Sahara War, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 32: 7)
  - Zionism, 1972-1981, undated
    - American Left - Jews, 1972-1981 (Box-folder 32: 8)
      Many of the articles discuss Jimmy Carter and a 1981 Camp David summit.
    - Anti- and Pro-Zionism, 1977-1980, undated (Box-folder 32: 9)
    - Zionist organizations, 1972-1976, undated (Box-folder 33: 1)
      Contains pamphlets, brochures, and other printed matter produced by the Jewish National Fund and the Association of Americans and Canadians for Aliyah.
  - Miscellaneous, 1968-1983, undated
    - Anti-Semitism and anti-Arabism in the US, 1973 (Box-folder 33: 2)
    - "Berrigan's Diatribe," Commentary, 1974 February (Box-folder 33: 3)
      Contains an article by Robert Alter regarding Catholic priest Daniel J. Berrigan's views on Israel given during a speech to the Association of Arab University Graduates on October 19, 1973.
    - Black affairs, 1973 (Box-folder 33: 4)
    - Border incidents and unification efforts, 1973 (Box-folder 33: 5)
      Contains articles regarding Egypt, Libya, Jordan, Lebanon, and Syria.
    - Editorials, 1980 (Box-folder 33: 6)
      Contains editorials, mainly related to issues in the Middle East, from The Washington Post, Christian Science Monitor, and The New York Times.
    - Ephemera, 1968, undated (Box-folder 33: 7)
      Contains a flyer calling for volunteers for kibbutzim in Israel, a flyer from the Association of Israeli Students, and flyers calling for donations to the Middle East Appeal.
    - Food crisis and aid to the poor, 1974 (Box-folder 33: 8)
      Mainly contains articles related to efforts by the United Nations, the United States, and other countries to aid the poor.
    - Human rights, 1978 January 29 (Box-folder 33: 9)
      Contains photocopies of two articles from The New York Times: "Rights, and Wrongs" by Jahangir Amuzegar which discusses human rights in non-Western countries and "Sadat at Camp David" by James Reston.
    - Husayn (Hussein) of Jordan's visit to the United States, 1973 (Box-folder 33: 10)
    - "Islamic Fundamentalism: Background file for new introduction,", 1972-1980 (Box-folder 33: 11)
    - Khartoum incident, 1973 (Box-folder 33: 12)
      Contains clippings related to the 1973 attack on the Saudi embassy in Khartoum, Sudan. Includes a news release from the US Bureau of Public Affairs dated April 17, 1973.
    - Kissinger, Henry, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 33: 13-14)
    - Kurds, 1974-1980 (Box-folder 33: 15)
    - Meir of Israel's visit to the United States, 1973 (Box-folder 33: 16)
    - Middle East activities in Ann Arbor, 1975, undated (Box-folder 33: 17)
      Contains a pamphlet advertising a demonstration in opposition to the Shah of Iran, an editorial cartoon from The Michigan Daily, a flyer for the Young Socialist Alliance of Ann Arbor, and an unsigned petition calling for legislation to forbid the introduction of US forces into the conflicts in the Middle East.
    - Military and politics, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 33: 18)
    - Munich Olympics and Lufthansa hijacking, 1972 (Box-folder 34: 1)
    - Nixon/Watergate, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 34: 2)
    - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), 1973-1974 (Box-folder 34: 3)
    - Sadat's speech, 1980 (Box-folder 34: 4)
      Contains articles in Arabic and English about the President of Egypt Muhammad Anwar El Sadat's speech on May 15, 1981 in which he abolished martial law in Egypt.
    - Solzhenitsyn, Alexsandr, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 34: 5)
      Contains various clippings about the Russian author and his writings, including a book review of his memoir The Oak and Calf: Sketches of Literary Life in the Soviet Union.
    - Terrorism, 1980 (Box-folder 34: 6)
      Contains three articles on world terrorism in response to embassy attacks and other acts of terrorism in Tehran, Iran; Tripoli, Libya; Kabul, Afghanistan; Islamabad, Pakistan; and Bogotá, Colombia.
    - Treatment of women, 1973, undated (Box-folder 34: 7)
      Contains articles relating to the treatment of women in Arab countries, China, and Pakistan. Includes an unpublished paper by Alf Andrew Heggoy titled "Cultural Disrespect: European and Algerian Views on Women in Colonial and Independent Algeria."
    - United Nations, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 34: 8)
    - United Nations and the Middle East, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 34: 9)
    - US and Arab-Americans, 1973 (Box-folder 34: 10)
    - Uzbeks, 1979, undated (Box-folder 34: 11)
      Contains two papers by William Fierman: "Uzbek Feelings of Ethnicity: A Study of Attitudes Expressed in Recent Uzbek Literature" and "A Soviet Uzbek Short Story as Mirror of Societal Conflict."
    - Unfiled articles
      - 1972, undated (Box-folder 34: 12)
      - 1973 (Box-folder 34: 13-14, Box-folder 35: 1-3)
      - 1974 (Box-folder 35: 4)
      - 1977-1978 (Box-folder 35: 5)
      - 1979 (Box-folder 35: 6)
      - 1980 (Box-folder 35: 7, Box-folder 36: 1)
      - 1981 (Box-folder 36: 2)
      - 1982 (Box-folder 36: 3-5)
      - 1983 (Box-folder 36: 6)
- Arabic Subject File, 1968-1982, undated (Boxes 37-39)
  Mainly contains newspaper clippings from Arabic publications, as well as other printed matter in Arabic. Original file names were written in Arabic script and have been transliterated. Arranged alphabetically according to the transliteration.
  - Adab (literature), 1979 (Box-folder 37: 1)
  - Al-Azhar, 1979 (Box-folder 37: 2)
  - Al-Iqtiṣād al-Islāmī (Islamic economics), 1979 (Box-folder 37: 3)
  - Al-Da'wah al-Islāmīyah (Islamic da'wah), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 37: 4)
  - Al-'Arab wa-al-duwal al-kubrá (Arabs and superpowers), undated (Box-folder 37: 5)
  - Al'Ilm wa-al-dīn (science and religion), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 37: 6)
  - Al-Fikr al-Islāmī (Islamic thought and civilization), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 37: 7)
  - Al-I'lām al-Islāmī (Islamic media), 1979 (Box-folder 37: 8)
  - Al-Khalīj al-'Arabī (Arabian Gulf), 1979 (Box-folder 37: 9)
  - Al-Sa'ūdīyah wa-iḥāth al-Masjid al-Ḥarām (Saudi Arabia and the events of the Grand Mosque), 1979 (Box-folder 37: 10)
  - Al-Sīrah wa-al-hijrah (biography and immigration), 1979 (Box-folder 37: 11)
  - Al-Taṣawwuff (Sufism), 1979 (Box-folder 37: 12)
  - al-Tarbiyah wa-al-ta'līm (education), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 37: 13)
  - al-Tārīkh al-Islāmī (Islamic history), 1979 (Box-folder 37: 14)
  - al-Waḥdah al-'Arabīyah (Arab Union), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 37: 15)
  - Ḥizb al-Taḥrīr, 1979 (Box-folder 37: 16)
  - Iran, 1979 (Box-folder 37: 17)
  - Islamic world - Turkey, Afghanistan, Pakistan, Arabistan, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 37: 18)
  - Libya, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 37: 19)
  - Majmū'at majallāt (magazine collection), 1976-1980 (Box-folder 37: 20, Box-folder 38: 1-2)
  - Miṣr (Egypt), 1978-1979
    - Aḥzāb (political parties), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 38: 3)
    - al-Dustūt wa-taṭbīq al-sharī'ah (constitution and application of Sharia), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 38: 4)
    - al-Qadāyah al-Miṣrīyah (Egyptian issues), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 38: 5)
    - Khutab al-ṣādāt wa-akhbār 'anhu (Muhammad Anwar El Sadat - speeches and news), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 38: 6)
    - Shakhsīyat (figures), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 38: 7)
  - Palestine, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 38: 8)
  - Qur’an, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 38: 9)
  - Ṣirā'āt wa-taḥaddīyāt (Islamic thought - conflicts and challenges), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 38: 10)
  - Sunnah, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 38: 11)
  - Syria/Aleppo, 1979 (Box-folder 38: 12)
  - Women, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 38: 13)
  - Unfiled articles, 1968-1982 (Box-folder 39: 1-2)
- Organizations File, 1967-1983, undated (Boxes 39-40)
  Contains newsletters, publications, and other material from organizations concerned with Middle Eastern and Islamic issues. Arranged alphabetically by organization.
  - Ad Hoc Committee for Academic Freedom, 1983 May 5 (Box-folder 39: 3)